Guide to the Max Lincoln Schuster Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Catalogued Manuscripts and Documents
  - Robinson, Hanry Morton. "Memo. on 'Vatican Report' by Robert Neville" (Box 8)
  - Russell, Bertrand. "Satan in the Suburbs and Other Stories" (Box 8)
  - Sandburg, Carl. "A Visit with Carl Sandburg" (Box 8)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur. "The Big Decision: Private Indulgence or National Strength?" (Box 8)
  - Schuster, Max Lincoln. "A Treasury of the World’s Great Letters" (Box 8)
  - Stevens, Wallace. "Talk for the American Federation of Arts" (Box 8)
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard. "Speech Accepting Gold Medal Presented by B.M. Baruch on Behalf of Interfaith in Action" (Box 8)
  - Lowell, Thomas. "Broadcast, May 14, 1948" (Box 8)
  - Trilling, Lionel. "And Shakespeare!" (Box 8)
  - Van Loon, Hendrick Willem. "For M.S. the ____ Introduction" (Box 8)
  - Van Loon, Hendrick Willem. "Pink Elephant" (Box 8)
  - Van Loon, Hendrick Willem. "They Cover the World" (Box 8)
  - Warren, Robert Penn. "Address at National Book Awards" (Box 8)
  - Wheelock, John Hall. "Conversations between John Hall Weelock and Davidson Taylor" (Box 8)
  - Durant, Will "The Age of Faith." 3 binders (Box 9)
  - Durant, Will. "The Renaissance." 3 binders (Box 10)
  - Durant, Will. "The Renaissance." Galley proofs (6 pages) (Box 10)
- Series III: Uncatalogued Correspondence
  - 1943-1950 & n.d. (A - Z); 1951 A - L (Box 11)
  - 1951 M - Z & misc. (Box 12)
  - 1952 A - G (Box 13)
  - 1952 H - R (Box 14)
  - 1952 S - Z & misc. (Box 15)
  - 1953 A - H (Box 16)
  - 1953 I - W (Box 17)
  - 1953 X - Z & misc.; 1954 A - G (Box 18)
  - 1954 H - S (Box 19)
  - 1954 T - Z & misc. (Box 20)
  - 1955 A - L (Box 21)
  - 1955 M - Z (Box 22)
  - 1956 A - L (Box 23)
  - 1956 M - Z; 1957 A - G (Box 24)
  - 1957 I - Z; 60th birthday letters; 1958 A - D (Box 25)
  - 1958 E - Z (Box 26)
  - 1959 (Box 27)
  - 1960 (Box 28)
  - 1961 (Box 29)
  - 1962 (Box 30)
  - 1963 A - I (Box 31)
  - 1963 J - Z (Box 32)
  - 1964 (Box 33)
  - 1965 A - O (Box 34)
  - 1965 P - Z; 1966 A - Z; 1964-1973 misc. (Box 35)
- Series IV: Simon and Schuster Material
  - Simon and Schuster Production Files (Box 36)
  - Simon and Schuster Production Files (Box 37)
  - Simon and Schuster Production Files (Box 38)
  - Simon and Schuster Production Files (Box 39)
  - Simon and Schuster Production Files (Box 40)
  - Simon and Schuster Production Files (Box 41)
  - Simon and Schuster Production Files (Box 42)
  - Simon and Schuster Production Schedules (Box 43)
  - Simon and Schuster Production Schedules (Box 44)
  - Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Editorial Reports (Box 45)
  - Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Production files misc. (1) (Box 46)
  - Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Production files misc. (2) (Box 47)
  - Financial Reports: 1935-1945 (Box 48)
  - Financial Reports: 1945-1952 (Box 49)
  - Financial Reports: misc. (Box 50)
  - Financial Reports: 1955, 1962-1964 Editorial Agendas: 1955, 1961-1966 (Box 51)
  - Sales Records: 1955-1962 (Box 52)
  - Sales Records: misc.; Publication lists (Box 53)
  - Book review lists (Box 54)
  - Book review lists (Box 55)
  - Books ordered (Box 56)
  - Advertisements (Box 57)
  - Advertisements (Box 58)
  - Clippings, articles, and advertisements: 1927-1929 (Box 59)
  - Clippings, articles, and advertisements: 1940-1960 (Box 60)
  - Clippings, articles, and advertisements: 1960-1961 (Box 61)
  - Clippings, articles, and advertisements: 1961-1962 (Box 62)
  - Clippings, articles, and advertisements: 1962-1964 (Box 63)
  - Clippings, articles, and advertisements: undated (Box 64)
  - Clippings, articles, and advertisements (Box 65)
  - Clippings, articles, and advertisements (Box 66)
  - "From the Inner Sanctum" column materials (Box 67)
  - Publishers Previews (Box 68)
  - Files on other publishers; mailing lists [Not found on shelf] (Box 69)
  - Catalogues -- other publishers (Box 70)
  - Catalogues -- Simon and Schuster (Box 71)
  - Catalogues -- Simon and Schuster (Box 72)
  - Rights and permissions (Box 73)
  - Rights and permissions (Box 74)
  - Rights and permissions (Box 75)
  - Pocket Books, Inc.: advertisements (Box 76)
  - Pocket Books, Inc.: advertisements (Box 77)
  - Pocket Books, Inc.: production files (Box 78)
  - Pocket Books, Inc.: financial and editorial files (Box 79)
  - Walter Winchell files: Strictly for Laughs: unpublished MSS, proofs and make-ups (Box 80)
  - Walter Winchell files: Strictly for Laughs: carbon copies and early MSS drafts (Box 81)
  - Walter Winchell files: correspondence, editorial files (Box 82)
  - Walter Winchell files: clippings (Box 83)
- Series V: Max Lincoln Schuster -- Misc. and Personal Material
  - Practice of Publishing (Box 84)
  - "Can College Students Read?" (Box 85)
  - M.L.S. personal research projects (Box 86)
  - M.L.S. personal materials (Box 87)
  - M.L.S. personal materials (Box 88)
  - M.L.S. personal materials (Box 89)
  - M.L.S. personal materials and photos (Box 90)
  - M.L.S. books, 73rd St. and Sands Point (Box 91)
  - M.L.S. books, 73rd St. and Sands Point (Box 92)
  - M.L.S. books, transferred to Sands Point (Box 93)
  - Books received by M.L.S., 1951-1955 (Box 94)
- Series VI: Author and Title File
  - A - Am (Box 95)
  - Ar - Bazin (Box 96)
  - Be - Bere (Box 97)
  - Berg - Bernays (Box 98)
  - Bernays - Berns (Box 99)
  - Bible (Box 100)
  - Bible - Bz (Box 101)
  - C (Box 102)
  - D - Dum (Box 103)
  - Durant (Box 104)
  - Durant (Box 105)
  - Durant - Dz (Box 106)
  - E - F (Box 107)
  - G - Ge (Box 108)
  - Gi - Ha (Box 109)
  - He - Hz (Box 110)
  - I - Kap (Box 111)
  - Kazantzakis (Box 112)
  - Kazantzakis (Box 113)
  - Kazantzakis (Box 114)
  - Ke - La (Box 115)
  - Le - Lerner (Box 116)
  - Lerner - Life (Box 117)
  - Life - Lo (Box 118)
  - Lo - Ma (Box 119)
  - Me - O (Box 120)
  - P (Box 121)
  - R - Rob (Box 122)
  - Rod - Rose (Box 123)
  - Rou - Russell (Box 124)
  - Russell, B. (Box 125)
  - Russell. B. - Sch (Box 126)
  - Sci - Shirer (Box 127)
  - Shirer - Sl (Box 128)
  - Socony (Box 129)
  - Soc - Som (Box 130)
  - Sp - Sta (Box 131)
  - Sto - Ta (Box 132)
  - Te - Tz (Box 133)
  - V - We (Box 134)
  - Wh - Y (Box 135)
- Series VII: Author Biography and Photograph File
  - A - Br (Box 136)
  - Bu - Den (Box 137)
  - Des - F (Box 138)
- Series VIII: MSS and papers
  - A Treasury of the World's Great Letters: MS & printed editions (Box 139)
  - A Treasury of the World's Great Letters: MS & printed editions; letters (Box 140)
  - A Treasury of the World's Great Letters: printed editions (Box 141)
  - The Wisdom of the Sages: MS (Box 142)
  - The Wisdom of the Sages: MS [Not found on shelf] (Box 143)
  - Oral History Memoir Papers (Box 144)
- Series IX: Address File
  - A - B (Box 145)
  - C - E (Box 146)
  - F - H (Box 147)
  - I - Mc (Box 148)
  - M - Q (Box 149)
  - R - S (Box 150)
  - T - Z; Foreign A - L (Box 151)
  - Foreign M - Z; misc. (Box 152)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 153)
- Series X: Miscellaneous Material:
  - Printed material/motion picture (Box 154)
  - Contents of the cornerstone Box from M.L.S. library at Sea Cliff, L.I., 23 May 1936 (Box 155)
- Series XI: Miscellaneous Simon and Schuster Material
  11 scrapbooks
  - Subseries XI.1: Cardfile: 1943-1948 and A-Z
    Quotations, most typed, some handwritten, on notecard-sized slips of paper, grouped and filed alphabetically by idea: [N.B. These were reBoxed from grey Boxes into cardfile Boxes and, as they were in some disarray, the contents listed are those listed on the grey Boxes -- e.g., the materials in Boxes 160-162 come from the grey Box marked as 1943-1945.]
    - 1943-1945 (Box 160-162)
    - 1945-1949 (Box 163-165)
    - Ability - Business (Box 166-168)
    - Business - Controversy (Box 169-171)
    - Controversy - Criticism (Box 172-174)
    - Criticism - Deception (Box 175-176)
    - Deception - Energy (Box 177-178)
    - Enmity - Experience (Box 179-180)
    - Experience - Folly (Box 181-182)
    - Folly - Friendship (Box 183-184)
    - Friendship - Greatness (Box 185-186)
    - Genius - History (Box 187-188)
    - History - Innocence (Box 189-190)
    - Integrity - Kindness (Box 191-192)
    - Knowledge - Literature (Box 193-194)
    - Literature - Man (Box 195-196)
    - Marriage - Moderation (Box 197-198)
    - Moderation - Mutuality (Box 199-200)
    - Opinion - Philosophy (Box 201-202)
    - Pity - Poverty (Box 203-204)
    - Power - Publishing (Box 205-206)
    - Publishing - Revolution (Box 207-208)
    - Reason - Self-control (Box 209-210)
    - Self-deception - Socialism (Box 211-212)
    - Society - Success (Box 213-214)
    - Suffering - Tradition (Box 215-216)
    - Tragedy - Universe (Box 217-218)
    - Universe - Wealth (Box 219-220)
    - Will - Women (Box 221-222)
    - Women - Youth (Box 223-224)
  - Subseries XI.2: Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books II: Subject file:
    - A – Ce (Box 225)
    - Ch - D (Box 226)
    - E - Ha (Box 227)
    - He - K (Box 228)
    - L - N (Box 229)
    - P - Sc (Box 230)
    - Sh - Ta (Box 231)
    - Th - W (Box 232)
  - Subseries XI.3: Author-title file (supplemental):
    - Durant, Will (additional files) (Box 233)
    - Wodehouse, P.G.; Peter Schwed -- Wodehouse editorial; files -- correspondence 1953-1975 (Box 234)
  - Subseries XI.4: Subject file
    - A - B (Box 235)
    - C (Box 236)
    - D - F (Box 237)
    - G - I (Box 238)
    - J - L (Box 239)
    - M - O (Box 240)
    - P (Box 241)
    - R - Sta (Box 242)
    - Str - Z (Box 243)
    - Materials re the censorship of Schnitzler's Casanova's Homecoming attempted by J.S. Sumner in 1930 Catalogued correspondence; arranged materials (Box 244)
  - Subseries XI.4: Uncatalogued correspondence:
    - A - G (Box 252)
    - H - O (Box 253)
    - P - R (Box 254)
    - S - Sh (Box 255)
    - Si - Z (Box 256)
  - Subseries XI.5: Notes, clippings, etc.:
    - 1913-1917 (Box 257)
    - 1918-1921 (Box 258)
    - 1921-1923 (Box 259)
    - 1922-1927 (Box 260)
    - 1925-1927 (Box 261)
    - 1927-1929 (Box 262)
    - 193--1932 (Box 263)
    - 1933-1936 (Box 264)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 265)
    - 1939-194- (Box 266)
    - 1940-1951 (Box 267)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 268)
    - 1953-1959 (Box 269)
    - 196--1962 (Box 270)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 271)
    - 1965-1976 (Box 272)
  - Subseries XI.6: Authors:
    - The Aga Khan III (Box 273)
    - Sir Max Beerbohm (Box 273)
    - Bernard Berenson (Box 273)
    - S.N. Behrman (Box 273)
    - Hsin-hai Chang (Box 273)
    - Will and Ariel Durant (Box 274)
    - Max Eastman (Box 274)
    - Charles de Gaulle (Box 274)
    - William Averell Harriman (Box 274)
    - Quincy Howe (Box 274)
    - Nikos Kazantzakis (Box 274)
    - William L. Lawrence (Box 274)
    - Max Lerner (Box 274)
    - H.L. Mencken (Box 275)
    - Martin Munkacsi (Box 275)
    - James Newman (Box 275)
    - Walter B. Pitkin (Box 275)
    - Bertrand Russell (Box 275)
    - William L. Shirer (Box 275)
    - Bradley Smith (Box 275)
    - Lowell Thomas (Box 275)
    - Jerome Weidman (Box 275)
  - Subseries XI.7: Subjects:
    - Culture and mass communications; great books of the western world (Box 276)
    - Great civilizations of history (Box 276)
    - Great masterpieces of literature (Box 276)
    - Great thoughts of great creative scientists (Box 276)
    - Ideas (Box 276)
    - Information retrieval (Box 277)
    - Libraries and reference books (Box 277)
    - Paperback publishing (Box 277)
    - Poetry (Box 277)
    - The practice of publishing (Box 278)
    - Society for the prevention of cruelty to readers (Box 278)
    - Spinoza (Box 278)
    - Wisdom of the (s)ages (Box 278)
  - Subseries XI.8: Simon & Schuster, Inc.:
    - Advertising notebooks (Box 279)
    - Advertising notebooks (Box 280)
    - Advertising notebooks (Box 281)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Children's books (Box 282)
    - Column (Box 282)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: The London Shakespeare; newsletter; paperback series; A treasury of the world's great letters (M.L.S. ed.) (Box 283)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: editorial research (Box 284)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Master plan (1) (Box 285)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Master plan (2); the Bible; Anton Chekhov (Box 286)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: S.L. Clemens; Confucius; Albert Einstein (Box 287)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Ralph Waldo Emerson; Benjamin Franklin (Box 288)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Great essays on life and death (M.L.S. ed.); William James; Samuel Johnson (Box 289)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Montaigne -- books used in research (Box 290)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Montaigne -- books used in research (Box 291)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Montaigne -- books used in research (Box 292)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Montaigne; Plato (Box 293)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Henry David Thoreau (Box 294)
    - The Inner Sanctum Library of Basic Books: Leo Tolstoy (Box 295)
- Subseries XII: Photographs
  - Photographs (Box 296)
- Series XIII: Books belonging to M.L.S:
  - "Bedside tray" -- books kept at M.L.S.'s bedside (1) (Box 297)
  - "Bedside tray" -- books kept at M.L.S.'s bedside (2) (Box 298)
  - Books -- inscribed, etc. (Box 299)
  - Books with notes by M.L.S. (Box 300)
- Series XIV: Oversized Material
  - World's Greatest Letters Sctrapbook (Box 665)
  - Photograph of Joseph Edward Davies, signed and inscribed to M.L.S. (Box 666)
  - Photograph of Abraham Flexner, signed and inscribed to M.L.S. (Box 666)
  - Diplomas: 1909 - Elementary School; 1917 - C.U. School of Journalism (Box 666)
  - Photographs (Box 666)
  - Oil Painting of M.L.S. (Box 666)
  - Purchase Book P, 1949- (Box 666)
  - Purchase Book, 1948-49 (Box 667)
  - Statues:
    - M.L.S.
    - Spinoaz
    - "The Sower" (Simon & Schuster trademark
    - Bas-relief of Lincoln
      Transferred to John W. Hill Collection of Lincolniana